Clyde Jones Papers 2004.0102
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Clyde Jones Papers
undated, 1962-1987.
2004.0102
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
2.5 Linear feet
The professional papers of Clyde Jones, faculty member in the School of Family Studies (Home Economics) at the University of Connecticut from 1961 to 1985.
Jones, Clyde.
Biography
Clyde Adam Jones, an artist and educator, was born in Cobleskill, NY, on November 10, 1924. Following service in World War II Jones received a BFA degree (1948) and an MFA degree (1954) from Syracuse University and an Ed.D degree (1961) from Pennsylvania State University. Jones taught art at North High School in Binghamton, NY, in 1948/1949 and from 1950-1956. He served as an Assistant Professor of art at Edinboro State College in Pennsylvania from 1956 to 1958. He joined the faculty of the University of Connecticut School of Home Economics and Family Studies as an Assistant Professor in child development, was promoted to Associate Professor in 1966, and retired as a Professor Emeritus in 1985. In 1978-1979, he was Assistant Dean of the UConn School of Home Economics and Family Studies.
Jones specialized in early childhood education in the arts and was active in related state, regional, and national associations in that area including the Connecticut Association for the Education of Young Children, the National Association for the Education of Young Children, the Society for Research in Child Development, the National Society for the Study of Education, the National Art Education Association, and the Connecticut and American Home Economic Association. Jones was an active ceramicist as well as an artist and had a number of one-man shows and group shows. He did the illustrations for a history of the School of Home Economics and Family Studies as well as for one of the School of Nursing at UConn.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the professional papers of Clyde Jones, a professor of Home Economics in the School of Family Studies at the University of Connecticut from 1961 to 1985. Materials in the collection consist of personal and professional correspondence, course guides, notes and manuscripts with annotations, publications, curriculum guides designed by Jones, record books, and other materials associated with his career at the university, primarily from the years 1965 to 1987. Subjects discussed in the collection include programs developed by Jones, such as his Activities for Young Children and Keeping Creativity in the Art Program for Young Children, as well as subjects such as Phi Delta Kappa, the Art Education course, the Child Welfare Services Summer program, and the Art Education Bulletin. The collection also includes numerous Christmas cards made by Jones, as well as photographs of ceramics and artwork, travel notes, A Ray of Light by Greta Pierce, and information on the Newcomers Club.
Arrangement
Series I: Papers ( undated, 1962-1987 ) contains, correspondence, memoranda, administrative records and class materials pertaining to Dr. Jones' employment at the University of Connecticut in the School of Family Studies, as well as many of his personal papers.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Jones, Clyde.; University of Connecticut.; Administrative Records.; Archives.; Correspondence.; Educator.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Photocopies.; School Records.; Storrs (Conn.); University of Connecticut.
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1962-1987
  - Class record books (11), undated (Box 1)
  - Postcard from W. Lure, circa 1980 (Box 1)
  - Documents related to courses taught, undated (Box 2:, Folder 1)
  - Activities for Young Children: a curriculum materials guide by Jones, undated (Box 2:, Folder 2)
  - Documents and articles written by Jones, undated (Box 2:, Folder 3)
  - NAEYC- New Orleans, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from University registrar's office, undated (Box 2:, Folder 5-6)
  - Keeping Creativity in the Art Program for Young Children" Notes and ms with annotations, undated (Box 2:, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from University registrar's office, undated (Box 2:, Folder 8-10)
  - Articles written by Jones, undated (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - Northeast AEYC, 1986-1987 (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - Letter granting life-time membership from Phi Delta Kappa, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 13)
  - Professional correspondence, undated (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Home economics, undated (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - HDFR 261, undated (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - CDFR 381, undated (Box 3:, Folder 18)
  - University Correspondence, undated, 1970 (Box 3:, Folder 19)
  - CDFR 281, undated (Box 3:, Folder 20)
  - HDFR 222, undated (Box 3:, Folder 21)
  - Certificate of Recognition, 1984 (Box 3:, Folder 22)
  - Radio-TV center, undated (Box 3:, Folder 23)
  - CV, 1973 (Box 3:, Folder 24)
  - Personal-University Records, undated (Box 3:, Folder 25)
  - CDFR 282, undated (Box 3:, Folder 26)
  - Art Education 3, undated (Box 3:, Folder 27)
  - Art Education 14, undated (Box 3:, Folder 28)
  - Day Care Centers Bibliography, undated (Box 3:, Folder 29)
  - CDFR 185--Hartford, 1962 (Box 3:, Folder 30)
  - CDFR 388, undated (Box 3:, Folder 31)
  - CDFR 261, undated (Box 4:, Folder 32)
  - CDFR 281, undated (Box 4:, Folder 33)
  - Bibliography on Creativity, undated (Box 4:, Folder 34)
  - CDFR 185, 1962 (Box 4:, Folder 35)
  - Art Education Bulletin article, 1963 (Box 4:, Folder 36)
  - Clippings on speeches, undated (Box 4:, Folder 37)
  - Western MA Assoc. for Nursery Education Speech, 1964 (Box 4:, Folder 38)
  - Newcomers Club, undated (Box 4:, Folder 39)
  - Bridgeport Talk, undated (Box 4:, Folder 40)
  - Storrs-Northwest (Goodwin) PTO, 1966 (Box 4:, Folder 41)
  - Professional papers, undated (Box 4:, Folder 42)
  - Child Welfare Services Summer Program, 1963 (Box 4:, Folder 43)
  - Center for Marital and Family Therapy, Annual Report, 1970-1980 (Box 4:, Folder 44)
  - Headstart Orientation Institute, 1966 (Box 4:, Folder 45)
  - A Ray of Light by Greta Pierce, undated (Box 4:, Folder 46)
  - Creativity and the Teacher, undated (Box 4:, Folder 47)
  - Adult Development and Aging and Gerontology Certificate, undated (Box 4:, Folder 48)
  - Human Development and Family Relations Program, undated (Box 4:, Folder 49)
  - Photographs of ceramics and artwork, travel notes, undated
  - Prints, 1976-1998; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 2005-0164_5)
    Scope and Content Note
    Subjects Include: Christmas Cards made by Clyde Jones.